Guide to Aden-Egypte - album of photographs by Sebah, Fiorillo, Zangaki et al AD.MC.027
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Aden-Egypte
Circa 1860-1890
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
Antiquariat Inlibris (1883-present)
AD.MC.027
125 Photographic Prints - Large landscape album (275x375mm). 125 albumen photographs.
An album of albumen photographs focussing on Aden and Egypt. It includes views of the Suez Canal and Port Said, details of architecture and mashrabiya (lattice work), landmarks, street scenes and historical monuments. Three quarters of the photographs bear the signatres of Zangaki (active 1870s-90s), Pacal Sebah (1823-86) and Luigi Fiorillo (active 1870-75).
Box 027
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions at akkasah.org. For access to physical album contact Akkasah Center for Photography, akkasah@nyu.edu +971 2628 5531
Immediate Source of Acquisition
.
Arrangement
Collection processed in the order in which it was received.
Biographical / Historical
.
Scope and Contents
An album of albumen photographs focussing on Aden and Egypt. It includes views of the Suez Canal and Port Said, details of architecture and mashrabiya (lattice work), landmarks, street scenes and historical monuments.
Three quarters of the photographs bear the signatres of Zangaki (active 1870s-90s), Pacal Sebah (1823-86) and Luigi Fiorillo.
Large landscape album (275x375mm). 125 albumen photographs. Bound in full burgundy morocco with title stamped in gilt lettering on the front cover, album sheets edged with gilt.
Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Suez, Egypt; Port Said, Egypt; Egypt; Architecture; Monuments/Memorials; Palaces; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Canals; Antiquariat Inlibris (1883-present)
- The front cover of the album 'Aden-Egypte'., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_afr01; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Egypt; Aden, Yemen
- The inside front cover of the album 'Aden-Egypte' with "J. Lenègre, 7 Rue Béranger" embossed on the bottom-left corner., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_afr02; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Egypt; Aden, Yemen; French Writing; Paris, France
- A patterned cover page., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_afr03; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
- A blank cover page., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_afr04; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
- The port of Aden (Steamer Point)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000001; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  French Writing; Ports; Aden, Yemen; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Coast; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Landscapes
- Barracks in Aden. (Aden, Les casernes, le mâl des signaux)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000002; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Photographic Prints; Aden, Yemen; Albumen Prints; Ports; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Coast; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Water; French Writing; Military/Soldiers; Landscapes
- The harbour in Aden (Aden, la rade, du mâl des signaux)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000003; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Ports; Boats/Ships; Water; Transportation; Buildings; Coast; Aden, Yemen; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Landscapes
- The post office; shipping agencies and peninsular and eastern companies (Aden, la poste; Agences des messageries et de la cie peninsulaire et Orientale)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000004; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Coast; Aden, Yemen; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Water; Ports; French Writing; English Writing; Landscapes
- The harbour in Aden (Prince of Wales Crescent - Croissant de P'de Galles)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000005; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Ports; Aden, Yemen; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Cattle/Cows; Animals; Carriages/Coaches; English Writing; French Writing; Hotels; Boats/Ships; Street Lamps; Landscapes
- Aden's city gate (Aden, La Porte de la Ville)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000006; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Streets/Roads; Doors/Entrances; Mountains/Hills; Men; Cattle/Cows; Animals; Aden, Yemen; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Landscapes
- The Catholic church and entrance to the city (Aden, Eglise Catholique, entree de la ville)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000007; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Churches; French Writing; Religious Sites; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Landscapes
- General view of Aden (Vue general d'Aden)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000008; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  French Writing; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Mountains/Hills; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; English Writing; Architecture; Street Lamps; Mosques; Landscapes
- The cisterns in Aden (Entrance of the tanks - Entree des citerns)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000009; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  English Writing; French Writing; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Animals; Transportation; Reservoirs; Aden, Yemen; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Agriculture/Farms; Dams/Barrages; Landscapes
- A view of a reservoir (Tanks No. 3, Citern No. 3, Cont 119369 gallons)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000010; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Reservoirs; Mountains/Hills; English Writing; French Writing; Men; Water; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Dams/Barrages; Landscapes
- A view of a reservoir (The tanks and the town, Les Citerns et la Ville)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000011; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Reservoirs; Bridges; Mountains/Hills; Men; Architecture; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; English Writing; Dams/Barrages; Landscapes
- A view of a court and the minaret in crater known as Al Manara Mosque or the Aden Lighthouse, Yemen (Aden, Le tribunal, La Tour de la Priere)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000012; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Government; Buildings; Lighthouses; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Mountains/Hills; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Law; Mosques
- The camel market in Aden (Camels Market, Bazar des Chameaux)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000013; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Camels; Markets; Buildings; Mountains/Hills; Aden, Yemen; Animals; English Writing; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- A view of the interior of a stronghold in Aden, Yemen (Aden, Intérieur de la Fortresse)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000014; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Buildings; Coast; Water; Mountains/Hills; Forts/Castles; Military/Soldiers; Tents; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Landscapes
- A group portrait of members of the Çomali (Somali) tribe in Aden, Yemen (Aden, Groupe de Çomalis)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000015; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Regional/National Dress; Men; Boys; Children; Group Portraits; French Writing; Weapons; Spears; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Aden, Yemen; Palm Trees; Outdoors
- A group portrait of the Çomali (Somali) tribe dancing with spears (Aden, Danse guerrière des Çomalis)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000016; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Men; Group Portraits; Dancing; Spears; Weapons; Aden, Yemen; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Regional/National Dress; French Writing
- A portrait of Le Khédive Mohamed Tewfik in Egypt (Egypte, S.A. Le Khédive Tewfik)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000017; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Swords/Knives; Weapons; Royalty; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Egypt; Fez/Tarboush; Uniforms; Facial Hair; French Writing; Medals/Insignia; Hats; Tawfīq Pasha, Mohamed, Khedive of Egypt, 1852-1892
- A general view of Suez, Egypt (Vue generale de Suez, No. 127)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000018; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Suez, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Ports; Boats/Ships; Water; Transportation; Mountains/Hills; French Writing; Landscapes
- A view of the landing area for ships in Suez, Egypt (Suez, La Ville, le Débarcadére, No. 125)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000019; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Suez, Egypt; Ports; Buildings; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Photographic Prints; Water; Albumen Prints; Coast; Mountains/Hills; French Writing; Landscapes
- A view of the train station and telegraph office in Suez, Egypt (No. 104, Station de chaimen? de for a Suez)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000020; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Trains; Transportation; Men; French Writing; Buildings; Suez, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Boats/Ships; Ports; Landscapes
- A view of Port Tewfik in Suez, Egypt (No. 138, Port Tewflick Suez)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000021; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Suez, Egypt; Ports; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Coast; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Water; Landscapes
- A group portrait of three men and a child at a shipping depot on the Suez Canal, Egypt (Le Canal, Une Gare, No. 127)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000022; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Men; Boys; Children; Hats; Coast; Water; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Uniforms; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Suez, Egypt; Canals; Group Portraits; Animals
- A view of the northern lighthouse in the Great Bitter Lake, Egypt (No. 21, Phare nord des lacs amers)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000023; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Water; Lighthouses; Canals; Boats/Ships; Transportation; French Writing; Lakes; Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- A view of the Suez Canal, Egypt (No. 22, Courbe d'El Ferdane)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000024; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Boats/Ships; Transportation; Suez, Egypt; Canals; Water; Coast; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Landscapes
- A view of the Suez Canal, Egypt (Le Canal, Une Gare, No. 38)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000025; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Canals; Coast; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Suez, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Landscapes
- A view of the curve of el-Guersh, Suez Canal (No. 49, Courbe d'el-Guersh)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000026; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Boats/Ships; Transportation; Canals; Water; Coast; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Suez, Egypt; Landscapes
- A view of the Suez Canal, Egypt (Le Canal, Une Gare, No. 78)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000027; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Suez, Egypt; Canals; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Buildings; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Men; Albumen Prints; Landscapes
- A portrait of a man standing at the edge of the Suez Canal in Egypt (No. 94, Courbe du canal)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000028; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Boats/Ships; Transportation; Canals; Water; Suez, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Individual Portraits; Coast; French Writing; Hats
- A view of Qantura (Kantura) Station in Egypt (No. 61, Station de Kantura)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000029; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  French Writing; Suez, Egypt; Canals; Water; Buildings; Coast; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Landscapes
- A view of a ship's arrival to Port Said in Egypt (No. 109, Arivée du Canal a Port- Said)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000030; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Port Said, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; Coast; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ports; Landscapes
- A general view of Port Said, Egypt (Port Saïd, La Rade, la Douane)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000031; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Ports; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Port Said, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Buildings; Canals; Landscapes
- A view of Port Said, Egypt (Port Saïd, Les Quais)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000032; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Buildings; English Writing; French Writing; Crowds; Boats/Ships; Water; Ports; Port Said, Egypt; Transportation; Hotels; Shops; Streets/Roads; Flags; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Carriages/Coaches; Advertisements; Men; Women; Landscapes
- A street view of Port Said, Egypt (No. 456, Rue du comerce a Port Said)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000033; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Streets/Roads; Buildings; Umbrellas/Parasols; Crowds; French Writing; Shops; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Hats
- A view of a park in Port Said, Egypt (No. 82, Place de Lesseps a Port Said)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000034; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Parks; Gardens; Buildings; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Port Said, Egypt; Street Lamps
- A street view of Port Said, Egypt (No. 451, Port Said Village arabe)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000035; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  French Writing; Mosques; Port Said, Egypt; Streets/Roads; Religious Sites; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Water; Ports; Donkeys; Animals; Men; Women; Children; Landscapes
- A general view of Port Said, Egypt (No. 452, Vue de Port Said)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000036; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Port Said, Egypt; Buildings; French Writing; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mosques; Landscapes
- A view of various streets in Port Said, Egypt (No. 69, Port Saïd Vue d'ensemble)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000037; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Buildings; Streets/Roads; Port Said, Egypt; Signs/Signposts; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Shops; Markets; Landscapes
- The lighthouse and exit of the Suez Canal in Port Said, Egypt (Port Said, Le Phare, Sortie du Canal)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000038; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Boats/Ships; Transportation; Ports; Water; Port Said, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Lighthouses; Coast; Buildings; Docks/Piers/Jetties; French Writing
- A panoramic view of Cairo, Egypt (4. View panoramique du Caire)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000039; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Buildings; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; Cemeteries; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tombs/Mausoleums; Landscapes
- A panoramic view of Cairo, Egypt (Le Caire, Vue panoramique)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000040; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  French Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mosques; Religious Sites; Buildings; Pyramids; Architecture; Landscapes
- A panoramic view of Cairo from Mokattam (No.5.F., Vues panoramiques du Caire)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000041; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Mosques; Religious Sites; Mokattam, Cairo, Egypt; Buildings; Bridges; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Military/Soldiers; Landscapes
- A panoramic view of Cairo from Mokattam (No.5.H., Le Caire, Vue panoramique)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000042; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Mokattam, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Crowds; Mosques; Religious Sites; Landscapes
- The Citadel and Mohammed Ali Mosque from Mokattam (Le Caire, La Citadelle, vue du Mokattam)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000043; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Mosques; Tombs/Mausoleums; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Landscapes
- The ablution fountain in the Mosque of Muhammad Ali in Cairo (Le Caire, Fontaine des ablutions, Mosqueé de Mohamed Aly)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000044; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Fountains; French Writing; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cemeteries; Architecture; Religious Sites; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt
- The facade of Muhammad Ali's tomb in Cairo, Egypt (282, Façade du tombeau de Mohamed Aly à la Giladelle)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000045; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Tombs/Mausoleums; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; French Writing
- The courtyard and minbar of the Mosque of Muhammad Ali in Cairo, Egypt (283, Intérieur de la Mosqueé Mohamed Aly)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000046; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Architecture; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; Mosques; Religious Sites; Tombs/Mausoleums
- An aerial view of the Mosque of Sultan Hassan in Cairo, Egypt (No.51, Le Caire, Mosqueé du Sultan Hassan)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000047; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan; Mosques; Cairo, Egypt; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Landscapes
- The mihrab in the Mosque of Sultan Hassan in Cairo, Egypt (326, Intérieur de la Mosqueé Sultan Hassan, (Mihrab.))., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000048; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Architecture; Mosques; Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan; Religious Sites; Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Arabic Calligraphy
- The interior of the Al-Azhar Mosque in Cairo (306, Intérieur de la Mosqueé El Azhar)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000049; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; Mosques; Religious Sites; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Albumen Prints
- The mihrab in the Al-Azhar Mosque in Cairo, Egypt (449, Mihrab de la Mosqueé El Azhar)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000050; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Architecture; Mosques; Cairo, Egypt; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Arabic Calligraphy
- Sabil-Kuttab of (Ziba Kaden) Um Muhammad 'Ali al-Saghir, Bab al Hadid (Caire, La Fontaine de la Validée, No.218)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000051; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Cairo, Egypt; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Architecture; Schools/Education; Fountains; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Arabic Calligraphy
- People standing in front of the Hotel Royal in Cairo, Egypt., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000052; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Streets/Roads; Carriages/Coaches; Donkeys; Transportation; Men; Children; Boys; Regional/National Dress; Hotels; Cairo, Egypt; Horses; Photographic Prints; English Writing; Albumen Prints; Street Lamps; Turbans
- The Ezbekieh Garden in Cairo, Egypt (N:105, grotte du jardin de l'Ezbekieh Caire)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000053; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Gardens; Parks; Al Azbakeyah (Cairo, Egypt); Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Caves; Water; Street Lamps
- The Ezbekieh Garden in Cairo, Egypt (Le Caire, Jardin Ezbékieh)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000054; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Parks; Gardens; Kiosks/Kushk; Buildings; Al Azbakeyah (Cairo, Egypt); Flags; Landscapes
- The Abdeen Palace in Cairo, Egypt (304, Palais d'abdin)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000055; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Palaces; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing
- The courtyard of the house of Count Gaston de Saint-Maurice (Caire, Le parterre de la maison du Comte St. Maurice, 401), on the corner of what is now Sherif Pasha and Qasr el Nil streets., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000056; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  French Writing; Houses; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Tiles; Embassies; Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Statues/Sculptures
- The courtyard of the house of Count Gaston de Saint-Maurice (Caire, Le parterre de la maison du Comte St. Maurice, 402), on the corner of what is now Sherif Pasha and Qasr el Nil streets., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000057; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  French Writing; Furnishings; Houses; Embassies; Tiles; Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Birds; Animals; Fountains
- The salon of the house of Count Gaston de Saint-Maurice (Caire, Le parterre de la maison du Comte St. Maurice, 401), on the corner of what is now Sherif Pasha and Qasr el Nil streets., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000058; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Houses; Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; Embassies; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Hand Fans; Pottery; Tiles; Chandeliers
- The salon of the house of Count Gaston de Saint-Maurice (Caire, Le parterre de la maison du Comte St. Maurice, 401), on the corner of what is now Sherif Pasha and Qasr el Nil streets., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000059; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Houses; Abdin, Cairo, Egypt; French Writing; Furnishings; Carpets/Rugs; Embassies; Pottery; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Lanterns/Lamps
- Bab al-Nasr (Gate of Victory) Cairo (128, Le Caire, Bab el Nasr, Porte de la Victoire)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000060; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  El Gamaliya, Cairo, Egypt; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Doors/Entrances; French Writing; Buildings
- A dock in Cairo, Egypt (N.382, Douane du Vieux Caire)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000061; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Albumen Prints; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Egypt; Boats/Ships; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Docks/Piers/Jetties; Water; Donkeys; Men; Animals; Coast
- A view of Cairo and the City of the Dead outside of the city walls (Boûl del la Ville (Caire))., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000062; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Cemeteries; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cairo, Egypt; Buildings; French Writing; Men; Group Portraits; Horses; Animals; Mosques; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Donkeys
- The courtyard of the Khanqah of al-Nasir Faraj ibn Barquq (Caire, La Cour de la Mosquée Sultan-Barkuk, 247)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000063; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Khanqah-Mausoleum of Sultan Barsbay; Photographic Prints; Tombs/Mausoleums; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Fountains
- A portrait of people in the City of the Dead in front of the Funerary Complex of Sultan al-Ashraf Barsbay (Caire, Tombeaux des Califes, 245)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000064; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Mosques; Tombs/Mausoleums; Architecture; Religious Sites; Crowds; Cairo, Egypt; Children; Boys; Girls; Group Portraits; Cemeteries; Photographic Prints; French Writing; Albumen Prints; Donkeys; Animals
- Two men by a grave in the the City of the Dead in Cairo (Caire, Tombeaux des Califes, 213)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000065; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Cairo, Egypt; Tombs/Mausoleums; Cemeteries; Mosque-Madrassa of Sultan Hassan; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Group Portraits; French Writing; Mosques
- Qasr El Nil bridge and barracks in Cairo, Egypt (No.281, Port-et Caserne de Kasr-el-Nil)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000066; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)
  Bridges; Nile River; Rivers; Palm Trees; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Military/Soldiers; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Cairo, Egypt
- A promenade in Gezira (Zamalek), Cairo (Le Caire, Promenade de Gézyreh)., Circa 1860 -1890; nyuad_pa000005_n000067; 1 Photographic Prints (Box 027)